title: LOTR (Medium)
category: Lord of the Rings

questions:
  - prompt: "What is the name of the wizard who turns Saruman’s staff white?"
    answers: ["Gandalf"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the tree that speaks to Merry and Pippin in Fangorn Forest?"
    answers: ["Treebeard"]

  - prompt: "What race is Gollum?"
    answers: ["Stoor Hobbit", "Stoor"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the dwarf who accompanies the Fellowship?"
    answers: ["Gimli"]

  - prompt: "Who is the steward of Gondor at the time of the War of the Ring?"
    answers: ["Denethor", "Denethor II"]

  - prompt: "Who is the elven lord who helps guide the Fellowship?"
    answers: ["Elrond"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the golden ring that controls the other Rings of Power?"
    answers: ["The One Ring", "One Ring", "The Ring"]

  - prompt: "What language does Aragorn speak when he reveals his true identity?"
    answers: ["Elvish", "Sindarin"]

  - prompt: "Who is the lady of the wood that gives gifts to the Fellowship?"
    answers: ["Galadriel"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the elven realm that the Fellowship travels through?"
    answers: ["Lothlórien", "Lothlorien"]

  - prompt: "Who is the leader of the Riders of Rohan after King Theoden?"
    answers: ["Éomer", "Eomer"]

  - prompt: "Who is the commander of the Uruk-hai army?"
    answers: ["Lurtz"]

  - prompt: "Who are the two hobbits that leave the Shire with Frodo?"
    answers: ["Samwise and Pippin", "Samwise Gamgee and Peregrin Took", "Sam and Pippin"]

  - prompt: "Who does Aragorn marry?"
    answers: ["Arwen"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the first battle where Aragorn proves himself as a warrior?"
    answers: ["Helm's Deep", "The Battle of Helm's Deep", "Battle of the Hornburg"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the land where Gollum takes Frodo and Sam?"
    answers: ["Mordor"]

  - prompt: "Which elf prince leads the elves to Helm’s Deep?"
    answers: ["Legolas"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the hobbit who borrows Bilbo’s sword, Sting?"
    answers: ["Frodo Baggins", "Frodo"]

  - prompt: "Who destroys the One Ring?"
    answers: ["Frodo Baggins", "Gollum", "Frodo Baggins, but Gollum bites it off his finger"]

  - prompt: "What is the name of the mountain where the One Ring must be destroyed?"
    answers: ["Mount Doom", "Orodruin"]

  - prompt: "Who says, 'There is some good in this world, Mr. Frodo, and it’s worth fighting for'?"
    answers: ["Samwise Gamgee", "Sam"]
